PREM VISPUTE

@ premvispute@gmail.com

Mumbai, India

J+91 9702714557

in premvispute

PremVispute

Portfolio Site

SUMMARY

Experienced in software engineering, full-stack development, and frontend engineering for 2 years. A professional merging creativity and technology, consistently infusing innovation into projects. Primarily worked with MERN stack with a knack for travelling and reading on the internet for latest technological developments.

SKILLS

ReactJS/Redux	NodeJS SQL/MongoDB TypeSc	ript Java GitHub Microservices Docker Agile
Python AI/ML Transformer Models(Hugging Face) Natural Language Processing (NLP) Tokenization		
nltk/spaCy simpleRAG ExpressJS HTML5/CSS3 Javascript/Jquery REST API NextJS		

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

M2P Fintech Pvt Ltd **SDE 1**

July 2022 - Ongoing

- Mumbai, India
- Led UI transformation of Core Banking System (CBS) application using ejs, JavaScript, and jQuery for Turing 3.0, focusing on optimal performance and responsiveness.
- Led a 5 member team for UI design evolution of Turing 4.0 (product) with styled CSS, emphasizing visually compelling and user-friendly interfaces, offering mentorship, ad- dressing obstacles, and playing an important role in task planning, assignment, and scoping.
- Led the migration of Turing 3.0 UI to React framework, introducing dynamic drag-and-drop architecture for enhanced agility resulting in a 98% reduction of time for developing UI interfaces.
- · Contributed significantly to backend development using Java and MySQL, ensuring seamless integration and functionality.
- Integrated Docker and AWS services for infrastructure optimization, implemented Flyway for database migration, and utilized Spring framework for application robustness.
- Orchestrated CI/CD pipeline integration to enhance reliability, scalability, and overall efficiency of systems by 50%.
- Tech Stack: ReactJS, NodeJS, JAVA, Javascript/Jquery, HTML/CSS

INTERNSHIPS

Nvest Solutions Pvt Ltd Software Development Intern

Dec 2021 - May 2022

- Mumbai, India
- Was tasked with web development for life insurance company websites, leveraged the C# .NET framework to craft intuitive and robust forms.
- Tech Stack: C# .NET, HTML/CSS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Al model for answering questions based on a PDF input.

- Developed an advanced question answering system as a simpleRAG using Python, integrating nltk, and spaCy for NLP tasks and custom-trained word vectors for improved accuracy.
- Implemented text extraction and processing from PDF documents using PyPDF2, facilitating efficient information retrieval.
- Conducted extensive data preprocessing and cleaning and developed a custom tokenizer for the same to ensure high-quality input for NLP models, resulting in improved model performance.
- Tech Stack: Python, nltk, spaCy, Hugging Face transformer (simpleRAG), Custom Tokenization

EDUCATION

BE in Information Technology University of Mumbai

Dec 2021 - May 2022 CGPA: 8.7

Thane, India